<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<MessageCollection xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="messagecollection.xsd">

  <Plugin>
    <ShortDescription>AWS Lambda SnapStart SpotBugs Plugin</ShortDescription>
    <Details>This plugin contains AWS Lambda SnapStart bug detectors.</Details>
  </Plugin>

  <Detector class="software.amazon.lambda.snapstart.BuildRandomReturningMethodsDatabase">
    <Details>
      Builds the database of methods which might recursively return a byproduct of a pseudo-random value.
    </Details>
  </Detector>

  <Detector class="software.amazon.lambda.snapstart.LambdaHandlerInitedWithRandomValue">
    <Details>
      Main detector to find out SnapStart bugs in Lambda handler classes.
    </Details>
  </Detector>

  <BugPattern type="AWS_LAMBDA_SNAP_START_BUG">
    <ShortDescription>Detected handler state that is potentially not resilient to VM snapshot and restore operations.</ShortDescription>
    <LongDescription>Detected handler state that is potentially not resilient to VM snapshot and restore operations in Lambda function {0}.</LongDescription>
    <Details>
      <![CDATA[
        <p>Our analysis shows that AWS Lambda handler class initialization creates state that might have adverse effects
         on the output of the function when it uses SnapStart. Lambda functions that use SnapStart are
         snapshotted at their initialized state and all execution environments created afterwards share the same initial
         state. This means that if the Lambda function relies on state that is not resilient to snapshot and restore
         operations, it might manifest an unexpected behavior by using SnapStart.</p>

         <p>Note that there are countless ways of initializing a Lambda function handler such that it’s not compatible
         with SnapStart. This tool helps you as much as possible but please use your own judgement to and refer
         to <a href="https://github.com/aws/aws-lambda-snapstart-java-rules/README.md">the documentation</a> for
         understanding how to avoid making your Lambda function SnapStart incompatible.</p>
      ]]>
    </Details>
  </BugPattern>

  <BugCode abbrev="SNAP_START">Potential SnapStart Bug</BugCode>
</MessageCollection>
